We have Shifra Williams, um, founding
DevRel from Render,
who will be showing an application with
Pydantic AI deployed on Render.
>> Hi everybody. My name is Shifra and as
Allysse kindly introduced me, I'm the
founding DevRel at Render. And this talk
is called what your AI pipeline does
when you're not looking. Spoilers, you
should be looking.
So, I want to start off by asking who's
heard of Render?
Awesome. Okay, great. Good amount of
people. Um, so Render, for those who
don't know, is the place where you can
deploy full stack apps and agents in
production. We hear a lot about agents
in dev, we don't see a lot about agents
in prod. And, uh, Render is really
simple. You select a service, this is
the lowest level of abstraction on the
infra that you'll deal with. You'll
deploy your code and Render is going to
do all the rest. Now, in the bottom
corner here, I did want to showcase
Workflows, our brand new service we
launched in open beta literally
yesterday. And this is durable,
resilient and long-running services
where, as you can see, agents can
attempt multiple times, checkpoint,
recover and run. So, if you want your
agents in prod, Render is the place to
do it. Now, what am I going to be
demoing for you all here today? Well,
I'm going to be showing you an
observable AI pipeline. As I said, you
should be looking, so we're going to
look. Um, and this AI pipeline is going
to use a Pydantic embedder, of course
Pydantic Logfire, Pydantic GenAI prices
to track the cost of AI queries, and of
course it's all going to be deployed on
Render. Now, you might have seen me
fiddling back there, that's because the
demo gods are not on my side today. But
you know what happens when the demo gods
condemn you, you throw it back in their
face and you make it part of the demo.
So, that's what we're going to do today
because we're engineers.
Cool. Let me jump into a demo.
So,
uh, what happened today was my database
decided to delete itself, which was very
great. I love when that happens. So, I'm
rebuilding the entire database in prod
right now. What I'm going to show you is
the observable AI pipeline that I built,
and then we can get into exactly what
went wrong and why it's still useful
even when it's going wrong. So, I'm
going to click this button that's going
to say, "How do I deploy an AI agent on
Render?" And as you can see, this is a
platform where we can ask Render
anything. It's an observable rag
pipeline with multi-query retrieval and
claims verification. So, as you see,
we're going to go through this
generation process that's going to track
the cost, and we can see the agent
writing something in real time. So,
what's going on here is there's question
embedding. So, what we're doing here,
and we'll jump into the code in just a
bit, is we are taking our question that
we typed in natural language up here,
which in this case was "How do I deploy
an AI AI agent on Render?" We are
embedding that using Pydantic's embedder
tool, and then we are actually throwing
that into our rag pipeline to retrieve
context from the Render docs, which are
loaded in here. We find those docs. We
build an answer. We isolate each claim.
What are the facts being claimed here?
And we look to verify those claims with
the context that we have in our rag
pipeline. From there, we can also see
all of the different sources that we're
checking to match against our claims.
So, these are like the articles that you
can actually jump into to verify, which
again, we should all be doing because
AIs can make anything up that they want.
We can see the different stages of the
AI pipeline and ensure that they've all
been successful, see how much each of
them cost, and then of course, we have
logs. And those are being pulled from
Logfire right here, which is showing us
all of these database operations,
checking our health, doing the question
embedding process, etc. And these are
the logs that are just coming in from
the latest runs here. And the health is
just going to keep pinging. Um,
and with that, we have this really
helpful article where
it's going to talk about the core
approach, how you can choose a
deployment pattern, which Render service
you want to use, whether it's a web
service, a background worker to scale
out, or of course render workflows, the
uh new service that I just talked about.
It shows us a production-ready example,
um and it has some key deployment steps
for us here. Then, we also have a cost
breakdown. Um we can see that by every
single step of the way, and we can also
see the evals here across OpenAI and
Anthropic models, both of which are used
because they're both good for different
things. So, we can also see the average
across the two evaluations to see the
agreement between uh the model evals.
So, this is really just showcasing uh
what Pydantic can do, and I want to show
you guys how
uh Render capabilities actually make the
broken prod demo even cooler than you
might think. So, of course, this is
running on my localhost because the
database decided to die, and that's
currently redeploying.
one of the really cool things about
Render is that our services are zero
downtime, right? So, even though it's
deploying my new updated uh
deploy command, the website is still up.
It's at this
logfire.renderfrontend.randomslug.onrender.com
for the subdomain, and it doesn't have
access to any context, right? Because
the database is empty. So, it's saying
to me, "I don't have any documentation
context loaded." But, it's still giving
me how to deploy an AI agent on Render.
It's still recommending Render workflows
for resilient long-running agents, and
it's still giving me basic deployment
steps without the details because it
doesn't have high confidence, it doesn't
have the context, it doesn't have the
sources, and yet it's still useful.
Broken demo is still useful and still
doing 80% of the value of the work with
sources. So, uh I thought that was uh
actually pretty cool to show, and I'm
I'm pretty proud that our product can do
something like that. So, let's jump in
to see this in action. We've already
seen all the logs in logfire, but let's
see how we actually built this. So, I
have uh a couple of files open for you.
I think this is clear enough to see. Let
me know if it's too small, but literally
such a great experience uh creating
Pydantic agents here. So, this is how we
create the claims agent. Uh I maybe
should be adding additional
documentation to this, but I can do that
another time. We're setting our OpenAI
chat model. Um, we're using the claims
model, which is, of course, a uh uh
Pydantic model that we've set up before.
We're using the open AI providers with
our open API key securely set in a
secret. We can have a special output
type that's using a predefined Pydantic
model class uh built off the base model.
And then we have the specific claims
extraction instructions, which are
listed above here. So, it's just really
clean, easy to read um agent agent code
here. Then we have the embedder using
the open AI embedding model in this
example, pulling again our open AI API
key, and then also setting our embedding
dimensions. You also might be wondering
where we're getting these prices from. I
am literally uh pulling the raw GitHub
user content from Pydantic's gen AI
prices because I want to see all of
those updates, and then I have some
cached values as a fallback, of course.
And finally, we have observability. And
one of the most fun parts of this is
seeing how we can just immediately auto
instrument all of these libraries
globally, so we can instrument open AI,
Pydantic, async processes, and
everything like that. And then we can
also define our custom logic for uh
instrumenting every single stage of this
pipeline with custom decorators that
wrap around. And finally, the last thing
I'd wanted to share with all of you is
the render.yaml. So, it it seems like
most of us here are building features,
building AI, and I don't know how much
uh people in this room want to be
wrestling with infra. And I personally
find render.yaml the easiest YAML infra
config file to read, uh much easier than
reading direct Kubernetes configs,
reading Docker files, which you can do
on Render, but this is uh much easier in
my opinion. And it's really just plain
English, really short lines, nothing too
complicated to follow here. And um
what's really fun about this is, for
example, we can have the prod database
using the PG vector extension. And then
one of the most uh annoying parts of
this would be storing the different
database secrets to pass around to your
back end and your front end. And we
actually have that uh automatically
populating. So, uh for example, we're
pulling the database URL from the
database ID using the connection string
property and we can just auto inject all
of those things. So,
you don't even have to do this. You can
do this with natural language. You can
use the render skills. You can use the
render deploy skill or the render MCP to
do this for you and essentially just
have all of your production services,
web service, back end, front end, and
database all talk to each other and I
just find it so easy to read, so easy to
configure and it's something that I
think is just a game-changer when you
don't want to think about deployment and
you want that to be
essentially vibe deploying at this point
in the game.
So, with that, I did want to offer some
really cool resources to get people
started on the platform so you can be
deploying your agents for free.
And the first QR code I have is for
people who might want to sign up to get
free credits. We're going to be giving
out $20 to $50 of credits. It's enough
to last a month or multiple months. So,
if folks want to sign up, the next QR
code that I'm going to show is where you
can request credits from me and as long
as you've signed up, I'll be able to get
those credits directly to your email.
So, I'll give just another moment for
that here and I think I did talk to some
folks in the front row who are already
signed up. So, get on the train,
everybody.
Cool. And then from there, you can now
request free credits.
Um
this is just going to get you into my
database and I can follow up with you
later to get those credits into your
email.
Awesome.
I also wanted to invite folks to join
the Render developers on Discord. We are
so excited to see fresh AI and agentic
use cases and we would love to see your
work. Potentially, if it's really
interesting, write a guest blog about
it, promote it, show people in the
community what you're building because
that's what we're all about is building
community around your prod AI agents.
And finally, I've linked the code base
so you can see how we've connected all
of these different Pydantic tools like
embedding, logfire, Pydantic agents and
deployed them on Render. So, if anyone
wants to check out the code base and how
all of that stuff works, it's linked
right here and I will fix the prod
deployment after this to get the
database working.
>> Thank you, Shifra.
Um lovely presentation. Thank you very
much.